Ken Wee Lubon Chin

Phone: +353 (083) 8837214 | Email: kenweechin@gmail.com

PROFILE

An experienced business-to-business and business-to-consumer Account Manager skilled in content management system, e-commerce platform management, implementing promotional campaign activities by utilizing email marketing tool, cross-selling, and customer relationship management. A confident communicator who takes pride in building business and achieving the target. Current role:

- Strong analytical and market research skills.
- Reduce procurement cost by analyzing purchasing data history.
- Improve the efficiency of commodity circulation.

CAREER EXPERIENCE

A&J Mobile Phone Accessories Limited, Dublin, Ireland

2018 - Present

Account Manager

2019 - Present

- Develop new product line and categorize customers to maximize business' turnover.
- Strengthen current business through constant communication and dependable product delivery.
- Supervise a team to conduct customer profile and behaviour analysis which captured sales opportunities.
- Led email marketing campaigns, social media advertisements, and tailored products accordingly.
- Liaise with procurement officers to maintain product data accuracy to enhance cashflow and mobility.

Key Achievements: Generated €45k sales revenue in the first quarter of 2021 by launching a mobile phone and laptop product line.

Sales Assistant

2018 - 2019

- Organized promotional materials for the new products through social media and email marketing campaign.
- Developed accurate financial records for the key customers to prevent overdue and outstanding payment.
- Managed purchasing orders and solved customers' issues by maintaining constant communication.

Excellence Logging Malaysia

2015-2016

Formation Evaluation Geologist

- Performed regular local risk assessment and minimized potential hazards.
- Collaborated with Wellsite Geologist for drilling log observation and interpretation.
- Administrated and examined all data as per client requirements and oil industry regulations.
- Carried out drill cutting analysis for the presence of carbonate material and lithological characterization.

EDUCATION

Code Institute Ireland: Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Present

Modules:

HTML, CSS, User-Centric Frontend Development, Javascript, Interactive Frontend Development, Python, Data-Centric Development, Fullstack Frameworks with Django.

CCT College Dublin: Diploma, Predictive in Data Analytics

2019

- Worked on predictive analysis of Black Friday sales data by collecting data from sales and organized,
 extrapolated data for drawing conclusions and business suggestion for the Black Friday Business Sales.
- Presented detailed report by illustrating data mining methodology applied and interpretation by utilizing data mining model.

University College Dublin: MSc Petroleum Geoscience

2016 - 2017

• Imperial Barrel Award 2017 participant for European Region.

Curtin University of Technology: BASc Geology

2011 - 2014

OTHER INFORMATION

Language: Mandarin (Native), English (Fluent)

IT: Microsoft, RapidMiner, Gitpod

Interest: Stock Investment, Cycling, Golf, Badminton